# Pranav Goel

Email: pranavgoel2012@gmail.com Figma: figma.com/@iipranavii Mobile: +91-9599091897 GitHub: github.com/iipranavii

### Summary

Creating Beautiful Designs with Memorable Experiences. Focused on designing products that are both accessible and interactive. My passion for human-computer interaction helps me observe what most people forget, thus helping me create designs that are unique yet familiar to use. I love working with Colors and Abstract Designs.

### SKILLS SUMMARY

• Design: Wire Framing, Low Fidelity, Prototypes, High Fidelity, Data Visualisation, Design Systems Storyboarding, User Research, Persona Development, User Journery, Usablilty Testing • Research: • Tools: Figma, Zeplin, InVision, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Blender, GitHub, HTML/CSS • Soft Skills: Leadership, Empathy, Writing, Collaboration, Critical and Creative Thinking

#### Experience

Quansight UX Design Intern Texas, USA (Remote)

July 2022 - Oct 2022

- o Accessibility Design: Researched on Accessibility in Data Visualisation and WCAG Guideline.
- o Design System Research: Constructed a mood board for company-wide design system with accessibility focused
- o Data Viz Mock-Ups: Implemented the Design System into currently used data visualisations, increasing visibility by 50% within the visually impaired TA.

**PeakMind** 

Bengaluru, India (Remote)

Jan 2022 - July 2022

- Product Design Intern
  - o Brand Identity Implementation: Built a foundational design system for the company, Typography, Colours, Brand Identity.
  - User Interviews: Conducted User Research analysing current scope of improvement and target audience comparisons.
  - Web & App design: Designed Mobile App Mock-ups and Wireframes with extensively re-usable design components.

### EDUCATION

# Chandigarh University

Punjab, India

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science; GPA: 8.58

Sept 2020 - June 2024\*

Courses: Operating Systems, Data Structures, Analysis Of Algorithms, Cloud Computing, Microservices, Networking

# Google UX Design Certification

Remote

User Experience and Interface Design

Courses: Moodboarding, Wireframing, Lo-Fi Design, User Research, High Fidelity Protoyping

### Projects

- SponsorBlok: (October 2021) StoryBloks, NextJS, AnimeJS, Figma
  - o Created a Cohesive Platform for Organizers and Companies to Reach out and Avail Sponsorships.
  - o Designed the Landing page and the Workflow of the Service.
- FeedbackPrime: (October 2021) Symbl.ai, Kotlin, Sawo Labs, Figma
  - Built an Intelligent system to understand and analyse the pain points during a customer support call.
  - o Designed an overnight UI to accept user's input and showcase a line-by-line output.

#### Honors and Achievements

- Selected as HackClub Leader Community for High school tech enthusiasts
- Awarded the title of Postman Student Expert.
- Won 1st Prize in API World Hackathon for Feedback Prime in Symbl.ai Challenge
- Won StoryBlok Track at Hack this Fall Hackathon for SponsorBlok
- Won the first-ever Postman API Fest

### Volunteer Experience

## Organiser - API Hacks

India.

Organized events, hackathon and conducted technical workshops reaching over 500 developers. Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

### Co-Organiser - Friends of Figma

Jalandhar, India

Organized virtual workshop and worked on resources to help 100+ designers.

November 2022 - Present